Guide to the Stanford University, Language Universals Project, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Language Universals Project, records
1967-1976
SC0449
Stanford University. Language Universals Project.
1.5 Linear feet
Records include correspondence and supporting documents from applicants for research positions, other correspondence, typescripts of their WORKING PAPERS ON LANGUAGE UNIVERSALS (numbers 1,3, and 8-20), bibliography, and the bulletin from the Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in Eastern Africa (1967-69).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Admininstrative transfer, 1986.
Information about Access
Partially restricted: applicant files are closed to researchers.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Language Universals Project, sponsored by the National Science Foundation, conducted crosslinguistic studies on various aspects of phonology, grammar, and semantics. It was directed by Charles A. Ferguson and Joseph H. Greenberg.
Description of the Collection
Records include correspondence and supporting documents from applicants for research positions, other correspondence, typescripts of their WORKING PAPERS ON LANGUAGE UNIVERSALS (numbers 1,3, and 8-20), bibliography, and the bulletin from the Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in Eastern Africa (1967-69).
Access Terms
Ferguson, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1921-1998; Greenberg, Joseph H. (Joseph Harold), 1915-2001; Stanford University. Department of Linguistics. Faculty.; Stanford University. Language Universals Project.; Africa, Eastern--Languages.; Linguistic universals
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Universals Project by Kurt Gottwald, April 10, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Universals Project by Georg Babiniotis (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Universals Project by Bernhard Rosenkranz, May 25, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Language Projects by Various Students, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Language Universals Project - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Language Universals Project - Correspondence (A-N), 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Language Universals Project - Correspondence (O-Z), 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Language Universals Project - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Language Universals Project - Applicants (1/3), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Applicants (2/3), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Applicants (3/3), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)